Hey, what are you up to?
مرحباً، ماذا تفعل؟
I'm just trying to roll a Yahtzee.
أنا أحاول فحسب أن أرمي حجارة النرد لأحصل على "ياتسي".
What's a Yahtzee?
"ياتسي" هي لعبة تقومين فيها برمي حجارة النرد هذه؛
five dice, and you try to get them all to match.
خمسة حجارة، وتحاولين أن تجعليها كلها متطابقة.
Okay, so like if I rolled all sixes.
حسناً، أتعني إذا رميت حجارة النرد وكانت كلها العدد 6؟
Well, not necessarily sixes.
ليس بالضرورة أن يكون العدد 6.
As long as they all match a single number, then that's a Yahtzee.
طالما أنها كلها تعطي الرقم نفسه فهذا يُسمى "ياتسي".
Okay, but why?
حسناً، لكن لماذا؟
I'm just trying to count how many times
إنني أحاول فحسب احتساب عدد المرات
I actually need to roll the dice to get a Yahtzee.
التي يجب علي فيها رمي حجارة النرد حتى أحصل على "ياتسي".
And I'm also waiting for my computer to reboot.
كما أنني أنتظر قيام حاسوبي بإعادة التشغيل.
Okay, well, I can help you out.
حسناً، يمكنني مساعدتك.
Thanks.
شكراً.
This is taking forever.
هذا يستغرق وقتاً طويلاً.
I know, right?
أعرف ذلك.
The odds are actually one to 1,296.
الاحتمال هو في الواقع 1 على 1,296.
So, mathematically speaking, we probably need to
لذا من الناحية الرياضية، سنضطر على الأرجح
keep rolling for like a thousand times to get a Yahtzee.
إلى مواصلة الرمي 1000 مرة حتى نحصل على "ياتسي".
That's a lot. We can always use a Java program to help us.
هذا كثير. يمكننا دائماً استخدام برنامج بلغة Java لمساعدتنا.
I've actually just written a function that simulates rolling dice. You should use that.
لقد كتبتُ بالفعل دالة تحاكي رمي حجارة النرد. ينبغي أن تستخدمها.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
أجل، تلك فكرة سديدة.
Why don't we use the while loops that we've just learned to simulate
لمَ لا نستخدم حلقات "while" التي تعلمناها لنحاكي هذه التجربة
Sounds like a plan.
تبدو تلك خطة جيدة.